<class>
    <ref>PHB p.87</ref>
    <name>Oath of Vengeance</name>
    <parent>Paladin</parent>

    <level value="3">
        <feature>
            <name>Tenets of Devotion</name>
            <shortDescription>Fight the Greater Evil. Face with a choice of fighting my sworn foes or combating a lesser evil, I choose the greater evil.
                No Mercy for the Wicked. Ordinary foes might win my mercy, but my sworn enemies do not.
                By Any Means Necessary. My qualms can't get in the way of exterminating my foes.
                Restitution. If my foes wreak ruin on the worl, it is because I failed to stop them. I must help those harmed by their misdeeds.</shortDescription>
        </feature>
        <spells>
            <spell>Bane</spell>
            <spell>Hunter's Mark</spell>
        </spells>
        <feature>
            <name>Channel Divinity</name>
            <uses>1</uses>
            <refreshes>short_rest</refreshes>
            <action  uses="1">
                <name>Abjure the Enemy</name>
                <shortDescription>As an action, you present your holy symbol and speak a prayer of denunciation, choosing on creature within 60 feet that you can see. That creature must make a Wisdom saving throw against your Paladin spellcasting save DC (8 + proficiency bonus + charisma modifier), unless it is immune to being frightened. Fiends and undead have disadvantage on this saving throw.
                On a failed save, the creature is frightened for 1 minute, or until it takes any damage. While frightened, the creature's speed is 0, and it can't benefit from any bonus to its speed.
                On a successful save, the creature's speed is halved for a minute or until the creature takes any damage.</shortDescription>
            </action>
            <action  uses="1">
                <name>Vow of Enmity</name>
                <shortDescription>As a bonus action, you can utter a vow of enmity against a creature you can see within 10 feet of you. You gain advantage on attack rolls against the creature for 1 minute or until it drops to 0 hit points or falls unconscious.</shortDescription>
            </action>
        </feature>
    </level>

    <level value="5">
        <spells>
            <spell>Hold Person</spell>
            <spell>Misty Step</spell>
        </spells>
    </level>

    <level value="7">
        <feature>
            <name>Relentless Avenger</name>
            <shortDescription>When you hit a foe with an opportunity attack, you can move up to half your speed immediately after the attack and as part of the same reaction. This movement doesn't provoke opportunity attacks.</shortDescription>
        </feature>
    </level>

    <level value="9">
        <spells>
            <spell>Haste</spell>
            <spell>Protection from Energy</spell>
        </spells>
    </level>

    <level value="13">
        <spells>
            <spell>Banishment</spell>
            <spell>Dimension Door</spell>
        </spells>
    </level>

    <level value="15">
        <feature>
            <name>Soul of Vengeance</name>
            <shortDescription>When a creature under the effect of your Vow of Enmity makes an attack, you can use your reaction to make a melee weapon attack against the creature if it is within range.</shortDescription>
        </feature>
    </level>

    <level value="17">
        <spells>
            <spell>Hold Monster</spell>
            <spell>Scrying</spell>
        </spells>
    </level>


    <level value="20">
        <feature>
            <name>Avenging Angel</name>
            <shortDescription>As an action, you can undergo a transformation for 1 hour, gaining wings and an aura of menace that frightens enemies.</shortDescription>
            <refreshes>long_rest</refreshes>
            <uses>1</uses>
            <effect uses="1">
                <name>Avenging Angel</name>
                <shortDescription>For 1 hour, you gain the following benefits:
                    * Wings sprout from your back and grant you a flying speed of 60 feet.
                    * You emanate an aura of menace in a 30 foot radius. The first time any enemy creature enters the aura or starts its turn there during a battle, the creature must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw against your Paladin spellcasting save DC (8 + proficiency bonus + charisma modifier) or become frightened of you for 1 minute or until it takes any damage. Attack rolls against the frightened creature have advantage.
                    Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest.</shortDescription>
                <speed type="fly">=60</speed>
            </effect>
        </feature>
    </level>



</class>