<class>
    <ref>PHB p.116</ref>
    <name>Divination</name>
    <parent>Wizard</parent>

    <level value="2">
        <feature>
            <name>Divination Savant</name>
            <shortDescription>The gold and time you must spend to copy an Divination spell into your spellbook is halved.</shortDescription>
        </feature>

        <feature>
            <name>Portent</name>
            <shortDescription>Glimpses of the future begin to press in on your awareness.
            When you finish a long rest, roll 2 d20s and record the numbers rolled. You can replace any attack roll, saving throw, or ability check made by you or a creature that you can see with one of the foretelling rolls. You must choose to do so before the roll, and you can replace a roll in this way only once per turn.
            Each foretelling roll can be used only once. When you finish a long rest, you lose any unused foretelling rolls.</shortDescription>
            <effect>
                <name>Portent: $roll</name>
                <variable name="roll" prompt="Enter a d20 roll"/>
                <shortDescription>You can replace any attack roll, saving throw, or ability check made by you or a creature that you can see with one of the foretelling rolls. You must choose to do so before the roll, and you can replace a roll in this way only once per turn.
                    Each foretelling roll can be used only once. When you finish a long rest, you lose this foretelling roll.</shortDescription>
                <context>LONG_REST, WEAPON_ATTACK,SAVING_THROW,SKILL_ROLL,SPELL_CAST</context>
            </effect>
            <context>LONG_REST</context>
            <uses>2</uses>
            <refreshes>long_rest</refreshes>
        </feature>
    </level>


    <level value="6">
        <feature >
            <name>Expert Divination</name>
            <shortDescription>Casting divination spells comes so easily to you that it expends only a fraction of your spellcasting efforts. When you cast a divination spell of 2nd level or higher using a spell slot, you regain one expended spell slot. The slot you regain must be of a level lower than the spell you cast and can't be higher than 5th.</shortDescription>
            <context>SPELL_CAST</context>
        </feature>
    </level>

    <level value="10">
        <feature >
            <name>The Third Eye</name>
            <shortDescription>You can use your action to increase your powers of perception.
            When you do so, choose one of the following benefits, which lasts until you are incapacitated or you take a short or long rest. You can't use the feature again until you finish a long rest.</shortDescription>
            <effect >
                <name>Darkvision</name>
                <actionDescription>You gain darkvision out to a range of 60 feet.</actionDescription>
                <shortDescription>You gain darkvision out to a range of 60 feet, as described in chapter 8. <!-- TODO --></shortDescription>
            </effect>
            <effect >
                <name>Ethereal Sight</name>
                <actionDescription>You can see into the Ethereal Plane within 60 feet of you.</actionDescription>
                <shortDescription>You can see into the Ethereal Plane within 60 feet of you.</shortDescription>
            </effect>
            <effect >
                <name>Greater Comprehension</name>
                <actionDescription>You can read any language.</actionDescription>
                <shortDescription>You can read any language.</shortDescription>
                <context>LANGUAGES</context>
            </effect>
            <effect >
                <name>See Invisibility</name>
                <actionDescription>You can see invisible creatures and objects within 10 feet of you that are within line of sight.</actionDescription>
                <shortDescription>You can see invisible creatures and objects within 10 feet of you that are within line of sight.</shortDescription>
            </effect>
            <uses>1</uses>
            <refreshes>long_rest</refreshes>
            <context>HIT_POINTS</context>
        </feature>
    </level>

    <level value="14">
        <feature extension="extend">
            <name>Portent</name>
            <extensionDescription>The visions in your dreams intensify and paint a more accurate picture of what is to come. You roll 3 d20s rather than two.</extensionDescription>
            <shortDescription>Glimpses of the future begin to press in on your awareness.
                When you finish a long rest, roll 3 d20s and record the numbers rolled. You can replace any attack roll, saving throw, or ability check made by you or a creature that you can see with one of the foretelling rolls. You must choose to do so before the roll, and you can replace a roll in this way only once per turn.
                Each foretelling roll can be used only once. When you finish a long rest, you lose any unused foretelling rolls.</shortDescription>
            <uses>3</uses>
        </feature>
    </level>

</class>