<class>
    <ref>UA, http://media.wizards.com/2015/downloads/dnd/UA_Eberron_v1.1.pdf</ref>
    <name>Artificer</name>
    <parent>Wizard</parent>

    <level value="2">
        <feature>
            <name>Infuse Scrolls</name>
            <shortDescription>You can also tap into your reserves of magical energy to create spell scrolls. You can use your Arcane Recovery ability to create a scroll instead of regaining expended spell slots. You must finish a short rest, then spend 10 minutes with parchment, quill, and ink to create a spell scroll containing one spell chosen from those you know. Subtract the spell’s level from the total levels worth of slots you regain using Arcane Recovery. This reduction to your Arcane Recovery applies until you use the scroll and then finish a long rest.</shortDescription>
        </feature>

        <feature>
            <name>Infuse Potions</name>
            <shortDescription>You can produce magic potions. You spend 10 minutes focusing your magic on a vial of mundane water and expend a spell slot to transform it into a potion. Once you have expended a spell slot to create a potion, you cannot regain that slot until the potion is consumed or after 1 week, at which time the potion loses its effectiveness. You can create up to three potions at a time; creating a fourth potion causes the oldest currently active one to immediately lose its potency. If that potion has been consumed, its effects immediately end.
                The spell slot you expend determines the type of potion you can create. See chapter 7 of the Dungeon Master’s Guide for complete rules on potions.
                Spell Slot Potion Created
                * 1st Climbing, growth, or healing
                * 2nd Mind reading or greater healing
                * 3rd Invisibility, superior healing, or water breathing
                * 4th Resistance</shortDescription>
            <useSpellSlot>true</useSpellSlot>
        </feature>
    </level>


    <level value="6">
        <feature >
            <name>Infuse Weapons and Armor</name>
            <shortDescription>You can produce magic weapons and armor. You spend 10 minutes focusing your magic on a mundane weapon, suit of armor, shield, or bundle of twenty pieces of ammunition, and expend a spell slot to infuse it with magical energy. The magic item retains its enhancement for 8 hours or until used (in the case of magic ammunition). You can infuse only one item at a time; if you infuse a second one, the first immediately loses its potency. Once you have expended a spell slot to create such an item, you cannot regain that slot until the item becomes nonmagical.
                The spell slot you expend determines the type of weapon, armor, or shield you can create.
                Spell Slot Item Created
                * 2nd +1 ammunition (20 pieces)
                * 3rd +1 weapon or +1 shield
                * 4th +1 armor
                * 5th +2 weapon or +2 ammunition (20 pieces)
                * 6th +2 armor</shortDescription>
            <useSpellSlot minSlot="2">true</useSpellSlot>
            <context>SPELL_CAST</context>
        </feature>
    </level>

    <level value="10">
        <feature extension="extend">
            <name>Infuse Weapons and Armor</name>
            <extensionDescription>You can create a second magic weapon, armor, shield or bundle of ammunition.</extensionDescription>
            <shortDescription>You can produce magic weapons and armor. You spend 10 minutes focusing your magic on a mundane weapon, suit of armor, shield, or bundle of twenty pieces of ammunition, and expend a spell slot to infuse it with magical energy. The magic item retains its enhancement for 8 hours or until used (in the case of magic ammunition). You can infuse only two items at a time; if you infuse a third one, the first immediately loses its potency. Once you have expended a spell slot to create such an item, you cannot regain that slot until the item becomes nonmagical.
                The spell slot you expend determines the type of weapon, armor, or shield you can create.
                Spell Slot Item Created
                * 2nd +1 ammunition (20 pieces)
                * 3rd +1 weapon or +1 shield
                * 4th +1 armor
                * 5th +2 weapon or +2 ammunition (20 pieces)
                * 6th +2 armor</shortDescription>
        </feature>

        <feature extension="extend">
            <extensionDescription>You can create a fourth potion.</extensionDescription>
            <name>Infuse Potions</name>
            <shortDescription>You can produce magic potions. You spend 10 minutes focusing your magic on a vial of mundane water and expend a spell slot to transform it into a potion. Once you have expended a spell slot to create a potion, you cannot regain that slot until the potion is consumed or after 1 week, at which time the potion loses its effectiveness. You can create up to four potions at a time; creating a fifth potion causes the oldest currently active one to immediately lose its potency. If that potion has been consumed, its effects immediately end.
                The spell slot you expend determines the type of potion you can create. See chapter 7 of the Dungeon Master’s Guide for complete rules on potions.
                Spell Slot Potion Created
                * 1st Climbing, growth, or healing
                * 2nd Mind reading or greater healing
                * 3rd Invisibility, superior healing, or water breathing
                * 4th Resistance</shortDescription>
        </feature>


        <feature extension="extend">
            <extensionDescription>You can create an additional scroll.</extensionDescription>
            <name>Infuse Scrolls</name>
            <!-- TODO this is rather complex -->
            <shortDescription>You can also tap into your reserves of magical energy to create spell scrolls. You can use your Arcane Recovery ability to create two scrolls instead of regaining expended spell slots. You must finish a short rest, then spend 10 minutes with parchment, quill, and ink to create a spell scroll containing one spell chosen from those you know. Subtract the spell’s level from the total levels worth of slots you regain using Arcane Recovery. This reduction to your Arcane Recovery applies until you use the scroll and then finish a long rest.</shortDescription>
        </feature>

    </level>

    <level value="14">
        <feature >
            <name>Master Artificer</name>
            <shortDescription>Your mastery of arcane magic allows you to produce a variety of magic items. You can create a single item chosen from Magic Item Tables A and B in chapter 7 of the Dungeon Master’s Guide. It takes you 1 week to produce such an item, and you must rest for 1 month before using this ability to craft another item.</shortDescription>
        </feature>
    </level>

</class>