<feat>
    <!-- TODO this doesn't display properly
    Ideally, would like the name under the choice, or at least modifiable from the choice-->
    <name>Elemental Adept</name>
    <choose name="elemental_type" title="Choose an Elemental damage type">
        <or name="acid">
            <name>Elemental Acid Adept</name>
            <shortDescription>Prerequisite: Ability to cast at least one spell.
                Spells you cast ignore resistance to the damage type of acid. In addition, when you roll damage for a spell you cast that deals acid damage, you can treat 1 a on a damage die as a 2.
                You can select this feat multiple times. Each time you do so, you must choose a different damage type.</shortDescription>
        </or>
        <or name="cold">
            <name>Elemental Cold Adept</name>
            <shortDescription>Prerequisite: Ability to cast at least one spell.
                Spells you cast ignore resistance to the damage type of cold. In addition, when you roll damage for a spell you cast that deals cold damage, you can treat 1 a on a damage die as a 2.
                You can select this feat multiple times. Each time you do so, you must choose a different damage type.</shortDescription>
        </or>
        <or name="fire">
            <name>Elemental Fire Adept</name>
            <shortDescription>Prerequisite: Ability to cast at least one spell.
                Spells you cast ignore resistance to the damage type of fire. In addition, when you roll damage for a spell you cast that deals fire damage, you can treat 1 a on a damage die as a 2.
                You can select this feat multiple times. Each time you do so, you must choose a different damage type.</shortDescription>
        </or>
        <or name="lightning">
            <name>Elemental Lightning Adept</name>
            <shortDescription>Prerequisite: Ability to cast at least one spell.
                Spells you cast ignore resistance to the damage type of lightning. In addition, when you roll damage for a spell you cast that deals lightning damage, you can treat 1 a on a damage die as a 2.
                You can select this feat multiple times. Each time you do so, you must choose a different damage type.</shortDescription>
        </or>
        <or name="thunder">
            <name>Elemental Thunder Adept</name>
            <shortDescription>Prerequisite: Ability to cast at least one spell.
                Spells you cast ignore resistance to the damage type of thunder. In addition, when you roll damage for a spell you cast that deals thunder damage, you can treat 1 a on a damage die as a 2.
                You can select this feat multiple times. Each time you do so, you must choose a different damage type.</shortDescription>
        </or>
    </choose>

    <context>SPELL_CAST</context>
</feat>